

Divya Shah

Roboticist | PostDoc



via S.Quirico 19D, Genova -16163, Italy



+39 3394143772



https://divyashah.github.io



divya.shah@iit.it

About me ——

I was born an brought up in Mumbai, India. The childhood fascination of robots lead to my involvement with the robotics club in my undergrad. That nascent exposure of designing robots motivated me to move to Europe and pursue higher education. Continuing the same passion, I obtained a PhD in robot design with the iCub Tech Facility at IIT in Genova, Italy in 2021. My doctoral research focused on mechanism design for wrist and forearm dexterity. Currently, I am continuing as a postdoctoral fellow working on mechatronic design and development of high power humanoid joint modules.

Skills —

Testing

Rapid Prototyping

Optimization Techniques

Trajectory Planning

Computer-Aided Design

Mechanism Design

Education

2017-2021 Ph.D. in Bioengineering and Robotics

iCub Tech Facility, Italian Institute of Technology &

DIBRIS, University of Genova.

2015-2017 Erasmus+ European Masters on Advanced Robotics

> (EMARO+) Genova, Italy & Nantes, France

University of Genova & Ecole Centrale de Nantes.

2011-2015 B.Tech in Mechanical Engineering Mumbai, India

Genova, Italy

Sardar Patel College of Engineering, University of Mumbai.

Research Experience

07/2021-present Towards Design & Development of ergoCub Humanoid PostDoc Fellow The postdoctoral research activity mainly focuses on mechatronic design and development of compact and high power humanoid joint modules for the new ergoCub project aiming towards human-robot

collaboration in warehouse and hospital scenarios.

11/2017-06/2021Design of Wrist & Forearm Mechanisms for Enhanced Humanoid Dex-

terity

The Ph.D. project aimed towards design and development of a 2-DOF mechanism for wrist application on humanoids such as iCub. It focused on employing parallel orientational mechanisms for increasing the range of motion, payload-to-weight ratio and mechanism isotropy of the wrist, thus enhancing the manipulation dexterity [J2, B1, C2].

07/2019-10/2019Design of Constant Length Tendon Routing Mechanism for Decoupled Motions Visiting Researcher

Collaborative project for idea generation, concept design and prototyping of a novel tendon routing mechanism through the pronation/supination (forearm) joint for multiple wrist actuating tendons

in order to allow decoupled motions between the wrist and the fore-

arm [C3].

02/2017-08/2017Increased Productivity of Automated Tape

Winding System

Master Thesis Intern

Collaborated on increasing the productivity of a kinematically redundant industrial platform for automated tape winding process. Focused on developing robust collision detection within workcell components and implementing time-optimal trajectories previously developed using dynamic programming principle. The simulations promised to reduced the overall processing time to one-third [C1].

Publications

2020	[C3] Constant Length Tendon Routing Mechanism through Axial Joint
2019	[J2] A Comparison of Robot Wrist Implementations for the iCub Hu-
2018	manoid [B1] Comparison of Workspace Analysis for Different Spherical Par-
2018	allel Mechanisms [C2] Workspace Analysis and the Effect of Geometric Parameters on
2017	Parallel Mechanisms of the N-UU Class [C1] Computer-Aided Design and Optimization of Redundant Robotic
	System for Automated Fiber Placement Process

[J1] Detection of Bimanual Gestures Everywhere: Why it Matters, What we Need and What is Missing?

Interests

2017

Swing Dancing; Hiking; Cricket; Ukulele